Guide to the Israel Cohen Papers Relating to His Book Collection
Israel Cohen Papers relating to his book collection,
ca. 1950-1986
M1001
Cohen, Israel
8 linear feet
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Notes and ephemera connected with the book collection that Stanford Libraries bought. Includes correspondence and publications. The collection is particularly strong in Jewish, Israeli, and Zionist history, dictionaries, encyclopedias,and books in the field of Hebrew language; translations into Hebrew of world literature; and most importantly, Hebrew literature, both ancient and modern.
Administrative Information
Access
All materials described in this finding aid are available for use without restriction.
Acquisition Information
Purchased with Cohen's book collection, 1994.
Biography / Administrative History
Israeli publisher and editor. Cohen was born in Galicia in 1905. He was a book lover all his life. He chaired Israel's Union of Hebrew Writers and published hundreds of articles of literary criticism. He died in 1986.
Scope and Content of Collection
Notes and ephemera connected with the book collection that Stanford Libraries bought. Includes correspondence and publications. The collection is particularly strong in Jewish, Israeli, and Zionist history, dictionaries, encyclopedias,and books in the field of Hebrew language; translations into Hebrew of world literature; and most importantly, Hebrew literature, both ancient and modern.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Book collecting; Judaica and Hebraica Collections; Israel Cohen Collection
Collection Contents
- Association Materials, Series 1.; 6 legal-sized folders
  Association materials: Materials pertaining to various associations to which Cohen belonged and committees on which he served.
  - Academic, Subseries 1.; 1 folder
    Most of the academic committees on which Cohen served are dedicated to the preservation and advancement of the Hebrew language.
    - Academic (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Materials pertaining to various academic associations to which Cohen belonged and committees on which he served; most are dedicated to the preservation and advancement of the Hebrew language.
  - Civic, Subseries 2.; 1 folder
    The civic associations to which Cohen belonged are dedicated to such matters as the naming of streets in Tel Aviv.
    - Civic (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Materials pertaining to various civic associations to which Cohen belonged and committees on which he served; they are dedicated to such matters as naming streets in Tel Aviv.
  - Cultural, Subseries 3.; 1 folder
    This includes a committee to memorialize Akiva Govrin and activities of AHIAM, an organization dedicated to the preservation and advancement of Israeli culture.
    - Cultural (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Materials pertaining to various cultural associations to which Cohen belonged and committees on which he served; these include a committee to memorialize Akiva Govrin and activities of AHIAM, an organization dedicated to the preservation and advancement of Israeli culture.
  - Political, Subseries 4.; 1 folder
    Meeting minutes and other materials pertaining to various political associations to which Cohen belonged.
    - Political (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Professional, Subseries 5.; 1 folder
    Materials pertaining to the activities of the Union of Hebrew Writers.
    - Professional (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Religious, Subseries 6.; 1 folder
    Form letters from various religious organizations such as Chabad and the American Jewish Committee
    - Religious (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Form letters from various religious organizations such as Chabad and the American Jewish Committee.
- Bibliographies, Series 2.; 1 folder
  Two bibliographies: Maamare Feytlson (5 p.) and Bibliyografyah shel kitve profesor Shmuel Werses, by Rut Shenpeled (9 p.)
  - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Book Fragments, Series 3.; 3 folders
  Partial copies of books whose condition does not warrant preservation and/or provenance does not warrant cataloging.
  - Book fragments (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Partial copies of books whose condition and/or provenance does not warrant preservaton or cataloging.
  - Book fragments (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Book fragments (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Book fragments (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bookmarks, Series 4.; 1 folder
  Cardstock bookmarks given away by publishers and other scraps of paper used to mark pages.
  - Bookmarks (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Compliments Slips, Series 5.; 3 folders
  Compliments slips (review copy inserts): Printed cards, form letters, and notes from authors inserted into review copies of books.
  - Compliments slips (review copy inserts) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Printed cards, form letters, and notes from authors inserted into review copies of books. Many include title page photocopies of the books they accompanied.
  - Compliments slips (review copy inserts) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Compliments slips (review copy inserts) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, Series 6.; 3 folders
  Correspondence: Miscellaneous correspondence from the 1930s to the 1960s, most not addressed to or signed by Israel Cohen.
  - Correspondence: 1930s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Miscellaneous correspondence from the 1930s to the 1960s, mainly not addressed to or signed by Israel Cohen.
  - Correspondence: 1970s and 1980s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Miscellaneous correspondence from the 1970s and 1980s; some not addressed to or signed by Israel Cohen.
  - Correspondence: undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Miscellaneous undated notes and correspondence.
- Greeting Cards and Invitations, Series 7.; 1 folder
  Contains greeting cards and invitations.
  - Greeting cards/invitations (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Greeting cards and invitations; mainly not personal in nature.
- Israeli Ephemera, Series 8.; 1 folder
  Israeli ephemera (miscellaneous): Printed matter pertaining to Israeli life in the 1960s to the 1980s, much of which apparently served as bookmarks. Of particular interest is a menu for a dinner honoring Prime Minister Golda Meir at the Sheraton-Tel Aviv Hotel, July 30th, 1969.
  - Israeli ephemera (miscellaneous) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Miscellaneous printed material pertaining to Israeli life in the 1960s to the 1980s, much of which apparently served as bookmarks. Of particular interest is a menu for a dinner honoring Prime Minister Golda Meir at the Sheraton-Tel Aviv Hotel, July 30th, 1969.
- Library Catalogs, Series 9.; 1 folder
  Three typed catalogs, two in German, one in Hebrew, listing books available at the library of the cultural center of the embassy of the Federal Republic of Germany. All dated 1977.
  - Library catalogs (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Maps, Series 10.; 3 folders
  Collection of maps of Israel and other parts of the world. Many were printed as newspaper supplements and given free to subscribers.
  - Maps (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Maps (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Maps (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Return Addresses, Series 11.; 1 folder
  Names and addresses on business cards and on scraps of paper torn from envelopes.
  - Return addresses (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Newspapers, Series 12.; 2 linear ft.
  Materials clipped or removed from newspapers.
  - Supplements, Subseries 1.; 4 folders
    Holiday and other commemorative supplements given free to newspaper subscribers.
    - Newspapers: Supplements (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Newspapers: Supplements (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Newspapers: Supplements (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Newspapers: Supplements (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Clippings Removed from Books, Subseries 2.; 1.5 linear ft.
    Most clippings have a title page photocopy attached. Many are book reviews or articles about the author.
    - Newspapers: Clippings: A (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Newspaper clippings removed from books with a title page photocopy attached. Most are book reviews or articles about the author. Each clippings is housed alphabetically by author of the book from which it was removed.
    - Newspapers: Clippings: B (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: D-F (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: G (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: H-J (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: K (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: L-M (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: N-P (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: R (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: S (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: S (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: T-V (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Newspapers: Clippings: Y-Z (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Newspapers: Clippings (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Newspaper clippings removed from unidentified books.
    - Newspapers: Clippings (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Notes, Series 13.; 2 folders
  Scraps of paper with writing on them. Some are notes pertaining to the books in which they were found; others served as bookmarks.
  - Notes (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Scraps of paper with writing on them. Some are notes pertaining to the books they came from; others served as bookmarks.
  - Notes (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Scraps and sheets of paper with writing on them. These include notes pertaining to the books they came from and notes for scholarly works; others apparently served as bookmarks.
- Offprints, Series 14.; 1 linear ft.
  From books and scholarly journals, many with inscriptions by the authors to Israel Cohen.
  - Offprints (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Offprints from books and scholarly journals, many with inscriptions by the authors to Israel Cohen.
  - Offprints (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Offprints (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Offprints (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Offprints (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Offprints (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Offprints (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Offprints (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Offprints (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Offprints (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Offprints (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Offprints (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Parshivot ha-shavu'a, Series 15.; 2 linear ft.
  Studies of the weekly Torah portion (parshah) by Nehama Leibowitz.
  - Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavu'a, Subseries 1.; 4 folders
    Printed booklets, arranged according to the five books of the bible: Bereshit [In the Beginning]; Shemot [Exodus]; Vayikra [Leviticus]; Bamidbar [Numbers]; and Devarim [Deuteronomy]. Each booklet consists of a study of the weekly Torah portion (parshah) by Nehama Leibowitz. Most are in Hebrew; the few in English are translated and adapted by Aryeh Newman.
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Bereshit (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Bereshit (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Shemot (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Shemot (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Vayikra (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Vayikra (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Bamidbar (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Bamidbar (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Devarim (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Iyunim be-parashat ha-shavua: Devarim (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Gilyonot le-iyun be-parashat ha-shavu'a, Subseries 2.; 1.5 linear ft.
    Typed sheets arranged according to the five books of the bible: Bereshit [In the Beginning]; Shemot [Exodus]; Vayikra [Leviticus]; Bamidbar [Numbers]; and Devarim [Deuteronomy]. Each sheet consists of a study of the weekly Torah portion (parshah) by Nehama Leibowitz. In Hebrew.
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Gilyonot le-iyun be-parashat ha-shavua: Bereshit (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Typed sheets, arranged according to the five books of the bible: Bereshit [In the Beginning]; Shemot [Exodus]; Vayikra [Leviticus]; Bamidbar [Numbers]; and Devarim [Deuteronomy]. Each sheet consists of a study of the weekly Torah portion (parshah) by Nehama Leibowitz. In Hebrew.
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Gilyonot le-iyun be-parashat ha-shavua: Bereshit (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Gilyonot le-iyun be-parashat ha-shavua: Shemot (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Gilyonot le-iyun be-parashat ha-shavua: Vayikra (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Gilyonot le-iyun be-parashat ha-shavua: Bamidbar (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Gilyonot le-iyun be-parashat ha-shavua: Devarim (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Parshiyot ha-shavua: Gilyonot le-iyun be-parashat ha-shavua: Devarim (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Photographs, Postcards and Prints, Series 16.; 2 folders
  Includes photographs and postcards of Theodore Herzl and other figures from Israeli history as well as art reproductions that accompanied art show announcements or that were included as supplements to newspaper subscribers.
  - Photographs, postcards, prints (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Contents include photographs and postcards of Theodore Herzl and other figures from Israeli history as well as art reproductions that accompanied art show announcements or that were included as supplements to newspaper subscribers.
  - Photographs, postcards, prints (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Programs, Series 17.; 3.5 linear ft.
  Event programs relating to all aspects of Israeli life.
  - Arts, Subseries 1.; 2 linear ft.
    Programs from the many Israeli arts performances Cohen attended.
    - Dance, Subsubseries 1.
      - Programs: Arts: Dance (Box 10, Folder 3)
        Three programs: The Paul Taylor Dance Company [appearing at Israel Festival Caesarea 1966], July 27-August 27, 1966;Shlonsk: lehakat ha-folkor ha-mamlakhtit shel polin be-mahol uve-zemer, September 17, 1966; Inbal: teatron mahol, undated ca. 1975.
    - Music, Subsubseries 2.
      - Programs: Arts: Music (Box 10, Folder 4)
        Six programs: Gertrude Holt, coloratora mezzo-soprano, June 8, 1958;Yiftah [Jephtha], G.F. Handel, The Moshe Zadikov Choir and Symphonic Orchestra, January 18, 1962;Israel Festival, 1963; Gala opening, July 16 - August 12, 1963;ha-Akademyah ha-yisraelit le-musikah be-Tel Aviv, Shavua ha-musikah ha-yisraelit, December 22, 1965; Moadon Milo, tselilim min ha-avar, introduced by Israel Cohen, May 1, 1973;80 yor moderne yidishe muzik, June 22, 1980
    - Opera, Subsubseries 3.
      - Programs: Arts: Opera (Box 10, Folder 5)
        Thirteen Israel National Opera programs: Faust; Alexandra; Kiss Me, Kate!; La Perichole; Aida; Tales of Hoffmann; Samson and Delilah [two copies]; Andrea Chenier; Eugene Onegin; Un Ballo in Maschera; Adriana Levouvreur; Otello; Aida; 1958 - 1974
    - Theater, Subsubseries 4.
      - Academic, Subsubsubseries 2.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron ha-Bimah (Box 10, Folder 6)
          Ten Teatron ha-Bimah programs: Per gint; ha-Erev Ionesco; Daber elai bi-veradim; Billy badai; Itsik Vitenberg; Nashe vindzor ha-alizot; Arturo Ui; Tartuffe; Shesh nefashot mehapsot mehaber; Mi yatsil et ha-falah; undated, ca. 1960s and 1970s.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron ha-Bimah (Box 10, Folder 7)
          Fourteen Teatron ha-Bimah programs: Bi-kets ha-yamim; Natan ha-hakham; Pegishah al ha-gevul; ha-Parisait; Masa le-niniveh; ha-Shekhunah; Komedyah shel tauyot; ha-Em; Per gint; Medeah; Pandre ha-gibor; ha-Ahim Karamazov; Retsah he-hapim mi-pesha; dated and undated, 1950s.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron ha-Bimah (Box 10, Folder 8)
          Eleven Teatron ha-Bimah programs: Lizistratah; Bikur ha-geveret ha-zekenah; Adon Biderman; Nitsots shel meshorer; Habet ahorah bi-zaam; ha-etsim metit zekufim; Bet ha-bubot; ha-Soher mi-Venetsyah; ha-Dod Vanyah; ha-Masa ha-arokh le-tokh ha-lailah; Nisuav shel ha-adon Misisipi; dated and undated, 1950s and 1960s.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron ha-Bimah (Box 10, Folder 9)
          Eight Teatron ha-Bimah programs: Milhamah ve-shalom; Beket o kevodo shel elohim; Hinaniyot ha-stav; ha-Beitsah; Anah kristi; Hezyonot Simon Mashar; Rekviem le-nezirah; Oliver; dated and undated, 1950s and 1960s.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron ha-Bimah (Box 11, Folder 1)
          Seven Teatron ha-Bimah programs: ha-Kisot; Tango; Shavru et ha-kelim; ha-Rotshim ha-ketanim: Komedyah; ha-Kayits; Dodah Lizah; Shimshon; dated and undated, 1960s.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron ha-Bimah (Box 11, Folder 2)
          Five Teatron ha-Bimah programs: Izun adin; Akidat Yosef; ha-Shahaf; Kolomb; Yehude ha-demamah; dated and undated, 1970s.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron ha-Bimah (Box 11, Folder 3)
          Five Teatron ha-Bimah programs: Halokh hazor; Troylus ve-Kresidah; Me-ever la-gevulin; Al kalut-daat ve-tseviyut; ha-Tiyul; dated and undated, 1970s and 1980.
      - Civic
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron ha-Kameri (Box 11, Folder 4)
          Seven Teatron ha-Kameri programs: ha-Drakon; Mehumah rabah al lo davar; Gibor ha-yom; En berirah le-hobson; Voytshek; Kineret kineret; Pigmalyon; Mari Styuart; dated and undated; 1950s and 1960s.
      - Cultural
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron Ohel (Box 11, Folder 5)
          Thirteen Teatron Ohel programs: ha-Poemah ha-pedagogit; Naarah la-ruah; Misrah tovah; Targil be-hamesh etsbaot; ha-Shabat ha-shehorah; Od nahar ehad; Hashmalit u-shemah teshukah; He-yadata et netiv ha-halav; ha-Ketubah; Kesher dam; Mar slon yekirenu; Shanim yemin; shanim smol; ha-Kad ha-shavur; dated and undated, 1950s and 1960s.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Teatron Ohel (Box 11, Folder 6)
          Eleven Teatron Ohel programs: ha-Perait; Adam hu adam; ha-Kamtsan; Hofre ha-zahav; Shorashim; Bet kevarot le-mekhoniyot; Mashehu lo normali; Gam hu ba-atsilim; Elef letsanim; ha-Holeh ha-medumeh; Maso shel Perishon; dated and undated, 1950s and 1960s.
      - Political
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 7)
          Six miscellaneous theater programs, dated and undated, 1960s, 1970s, and 1980s.
        - Programs: Arts: Theater: Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Public, Subseries 2.; 1.5 linear ft.
    Programs sponsored by academic, civic, cultural, political, professional, and religious organizations.
    - Academic, Subsubseries 1.
      - Programs: Public: Academic (Box 12, Folder 1)
        Invitations and announcements regarding events sponsored by academic institutions. 1960s - 1990s.
    - Civic, Subsubseries 2.
      - Programs: Public: Civic (Box 12, Folder 2)
        Invitations and announcements regarding events sponsored by civic institutions. 1960s - 1980s.
    - Cultural, Subsubseries 3.
      - Programs: Public: Cultural (Box 12, Folder 3)
        Invitations and announcements regarding events sponsored by cultural organizations. 1950s - 1980s.
      - Programs: Public: Cultural (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Programs: Public: Cultural (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Political, Subsubseries 4.
      - Programs: Public: Political (Box 12, Folder 6)
        Invitations and announcements regarding events sponsored by political organizations. 1960s - 1980s.
    - Professional, Subseries 5.
      - Programs: Public: Professional (Box 12, Folder 7)
        Invitations and announcements regarding events sponsored by professional organizations. 1960s - 1980s.
    - Religious, Subsubseries 6.
      - Programs: Public: Religious (Box 12, Folder 8)
        Invitations and announcements regarding events sponsored by religious organizations. 1960s - 1980s.
- Publisher Materials, Series 18.; 2 linear ft.
  Materials from publishers in Israel and abroad.
  - Catalogs and Pricelists, Subseries 1.; 9 folders
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Catalogs and pricelists from many publishers, both Israeli and from abroad. Formats range from single typed sheets to pamphlets and booklets.
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Publisher materials: Catalogs/pricelists (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Publication Announcements and Order Forms, Subseries 2.; 2 folders
    Pamphlets and single sheets announcing book publications and offering them for purchase.
    - Publisher materials: Publication announcements/order forms (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Publisher materials: Publication announcements/order forms (Box 14, Folder 3)
- School Materials, Series 19.; 3 folders
  Materials relating to educational institutions.
  - Catalogs, Subseries 1.; 1 folder
    Catalog from Bet Berl outlining programs and course offerings. 1957-1958 school year.
    - School materials: catalogs (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Exams, Subseries 2.; 1 folder
    - School materials: exams (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Three exams: Israel Ministry of Education and Culture exam in Hebrew language for unaccredited teachers, dated Summer, 1960; Tel Aviv University exam in Hebrew literature (for a course taught by Cohen's daughter Nurit Govrin), Dec. 1965 [two copies]; Israel Ministry of Education and Culture high school baccalaureate exam in Hebrew literature, dated Summer, 1967.
  - Syllabi, Subseries 3.; 1 folder
    Tel Aviv University syllabus for course taught by Cohen's daughter Prof. Nurit Govrin: ha-Merkaz ha-sifruti ha-ivri be-artsot ha-berit [The Hebrew literary center in the United States]; first semester 1983; Source list for course taught by Dr. Gavriel Hayim Cohen: Mavo le-midrash ule-agadah, undated.
    - School materials: syllabi (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Tel Aviv University syllabus for course taught by Cohen's daughter Prof. Nurit Govrin: ha-Merkaz ha-sifruti ha-ivri be-artsot ha-berit [The Hebrew literary center in the United States]; first semester 1983;Source list for course taught by Dr. Gavriel Hayim Cohen: Mavo le-midrash ule-agadah, undated.
- Serials, Series 20.; 12 folders
  Single issues of 12 different serials. In Hebrew, dated 1862 to 1980s.
  - Serials: Alon ha-kefar [Moshav Nahalal] no. 289; 1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Single issue of Moshav Nahalal's newsletter, 1982.
  - Serials: Daf meda [Universitat Tel Aviv]; 1981 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Information sheet from the archive of ha-Mahon le-heker ha-tefutsot [Institute for Diaspora Studies] at Tel Aviv University, October, 1981.
  - Serials: Davar li-yeladim, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Supplement for children from the daily newspaper Davar: vol. 17, no. 8; Nov. 28, 1946.
  - Serials: Davar Eilat, ca. 1957. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Newsletter published by the local council and the worker's council of the city of Eilat. Ca. 1957.
  - Serials: HUL Notes [Harvard University Library]; 1975. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Newsletter published by the Harvard University Library; no. 325, May 8, 1975.
  - Iton rishmi; 1948 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Iton rishmi [official newspaper]; contains the declaration of the establishment of the State of Israel. 3 p. No. 1, May 14, 1948.
  - Serials: Moznayim 1933 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Moznayim: shavuon li-sifrut, le-bikoret, ule-divre omanut [cultural journal published by the Union of Hebrew Writers in Palestine. No. 1 (201). Tel Aviv: Aug. 16, 1933.
  - Serials: Nisan: measef arukh bi-yede Yaakov Fikhman. 1930. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Hebrew literary journal containing inscription by editor Yaakov Fikhman to David Shmuelevits. Warsaw: Spring, 1930.
  - Serials: Peulot bet berl. 1971. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Newsletter of Bet Berl college. Edited by Daniel Cohen-Sagi, May 1971.
  - Serials: Rashe perakim le-hasbarah, no. 35. (Box 14, Folder 16)